Arizona Copper Company records, 1882-1922
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Arizona Copper Company records, 1882-1922
AZ 146
Arizona Copper Company
Business records of the company pertaining to administration of its copper mines which included the Longfellow Mine, Coronado Mine, Metcalf Mine, Clay Mine, and Humboldt Mine. Records include financial journals, ledgers, cost statements; payroll records, including accident reports and industrial compensation; production and sales records and inventories. Also included are records of the Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company; Clifton Hospital; and Metcalf Hospital; which were owned by the company.
30 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Arizona Copper Company was a mining company of Edinburgh, Scotland, operating in the Clifton- Morenci area of Arizona from 1882-1921. The company was sold to Phelps Dodge Corporation in 1921.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series:
Series I: Financial Records and Related Material, 1882-1922
Series II: Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company Records, 1890-1919
Series III: Records of Injured Persons, 1912-1921
Series IV: Production and Sales Records, 1893-1921
Series V: Miscellaneous Financial Records (Microfiche), 1909-1921
Scope and Content Note
Business records of the company pertaining to administration of its copper mines which included the Longfellow Mine, Coronado Mine, Metcalf Mine, Clay Mine, and Humboldt Mine. Records include financial journals, ledgers, cost statements; payroll records, including accident reports and industrial compensation; production and sales records and inventories. Also included are records of the Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company; Clifton Hospital; and Metcalf Hospital; which were owned by the company.
Access Terms
Clifton Hospital (Ariz.)
Metcalf Hospital (Ariz.)
Arizona Copper Company -- Archives
Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company
Copper mines and mining -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mineral industries -- Arizona -- Finance -- Sources
Railroad companies -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Hospitals -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Copper miners -- History -- Sources
Humboldt Mine (Ariz.)
Clay Mine (Ariz.)
Longfellow Mine (Ariz.)
Coronado Mine (Ariz.)
Coronado Mine (Ariz.)
Ledgers
Inventories
Payrolls
Container List
- Series I: Financial Records and Related Material, 1882-1922
  - Journal A. October 1882-December 1886 (Volume 1)
  - Journal B. January 1887-April 1891 (Volume 2)
  - Journal C. April 1891-October 1894 (Volume 3)
  - Journal D. October 1894-May 1897 (Volume 4)
  - Journal E. June 1897-October 1899 (Volume 5)
  - Journal F. October 1899-August 1901 (Volume 6)
  - Journal G. September 1901-May 1903 (Volume 7)
  - Journal H. June 1903-January 1905 (Volume 8)
  - Journal I. February 1905-June 1906 (Volume 9)
  - Journal J. July 1906-December 1907 (Volume 10)
  - Journal K. January 1908-July 1909 (Volume 11)
  - Journal L. August 1909-September 1912 (Volume 12)
  - Journal M. October 1912-May 1916 (Volume 13)
    Journal N is missing.
  - Journal O. January 1920-January 1922 (Volume 14)
  - Ledger A. September 1882-March 1883 (Volume 15)
  - Ledger B. April 1883-September 1884 (Volume 16)
  - Ledger C. October 1884-September 1893 (Volume 17)
  - Ledger D. October 1893-September 1899 (Volume 18)
  - Ledger E. October 1899-December 1902 (Volume 19)
  - Ledger F. January 1903-March 1905 (Volume 20)
  - Ledger G. April 1905-March 1907 (Volume 21)
  - Ledger H. April 1907-September 1909 (Volume 22)
  - Ledger I. October 1909-March 1914 (Volume 23)
  - Ledger J. April 1914-March 1919 (Volume 24)
  - Ledger K. April 1919-December 1921 (Volume 25)
  - Ledger "1" (Kansas City). September 1882-September 1889 (Volume 26)
  - Ledger "2" (Kansas City). April 1883-October 1884 (Volume 27)
  - Cash Book and Journal: L. Underwood, General Manager, Kansas City. September 1882-August 1885 (Volume 28)
  - Cash Book and Journal: Kansas City. April 1883-February 1885 (Volume 29)
  - Ledger: Private Accounts. October 1902-January 1908 (Volume 30)
  - Ledger. 1907-1909 (Volume 31)
  - Ledger. 1908 (Volume 32)
  - Cash Book A. April 1883-November 1886 (Volume 33)
  - Cash Book B. December 1886-September 1893 (Volume 34)
  - Cash Book C. October 1893-March 1897 (Volume 35)
  - Cash Book D. April 1897-September 1899 (Volume 36)
  - Cash Book E. October 1899-September 1901 (Volume 37)
  - Cash Book F. October 1901-September 1902 (Volume 38)
  - Cash Book G. October 1902-November 1903 (Volume 39)
  - Cash Book H. December 1903-November 1904 (Volume 40)
  - Cash Book I. December 1904-November 1905 (Volume 41)
  - Cash Book J. December 1905-September 1906 (Volume 42)
  - Cash Book K. October 1906-July 1907 (Volume 43)
  - Cash Book L. August 1907-January 1909 (Volume 44)
  - Cash Book M. February 1909-January 1911 (Volume 45)
  - Cash Book N. February 1911-August 1912 (Volume 46)
  - Cash Book O. September 1912-October 1913 (Volume 47)
  - Cash Book P. November 1913-December 1914 (Volume 48)
  - Cash Book Q. January 1915-April 1916 (Volume 49)
  - Cash Book R. May 1916-June 1917 (Volume 50)
  - Cash Book S. July 1917-August 1918 (Volume 51)
  - Cash Book T. September 1918-October 1919 (Volume 52)
  - Cash Book U. November 1919-January 1921 (Volume 53)
  - Cash Book V. February 1921-December 1921 (Volume 54)
  - Memo Cash Book. January 1890-September 1893 (Volume 55)
  - Memo Cash Book. October 1893-July 1896 (Volume 56)
  - Memo Cash Book. August 1896-June 1898 (Volume 57)
  - Memo Cash Book. July-September 1898 (Volume 58)
  - Cash Ledger. August 1900-March 1902 (Volume 59)
  - Cash Ledger A. Aril 1902-December 1903 (Volume 60)
  - Cash Ledger B. January 1904-October 1905 (Volume 61)
    Cash Ledger C is missing.
  - Cash Ledger D. January 1907-January 1908 (Volume 62)
  - Cash Ledger E. February 1908-August 1909 (Volume 63)
  - Cash Ledger F. September 1909-June 1911 (Volume 64)
  - Cash Ledger G. July 1911-March 1913 (Volume 65)
  - Cash Ledger H. April 1913-June 1915 (Volume 66)
  - Cash Ledger I. July 1915-August 1918 (Volume 67)
  - Cost Statement. October 1884-March 1892 (Volume 68)
  - Cost Statement. April 1892-March 1899 (Volume 69)
  - Cost Statement. April 1899-September 1905 (Volume 70)
  - Mining Cost Sheet. 1914-1919 (Box 71)
  - Mining Department: Cost Statements. 1918-1922 (Box 72, Folder 1-3)
  - Mining Department: Report of Mining Operations. October 1914-September 1917 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Mining Department: Segregation of Air Compression. January 1918-September 1920 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Mining Department: Statement of Ore Shipments and Production. October 1913-June 1921 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Monthly Concentrator Costs. October 1909-June 1917 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Leasing Department: Statement of Settlements. April 1908-April 1921 (Box 73, Folder 1-2)
  - Leasing Department: Leasers' Supply Statements and/or Accounts. April 1917-October 1920 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Leasing Department: Segregation of Accounts. May 1917-April 1921 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Leasing Department: Miscellaneous Reports. (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Power Department: Monthly Electrical Log. August 1914-September 1920 (Box 73, Folder 6-7)
  - Miscellaneous Records: Castings, general supplies, power. July 1913-March 1916 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: Lumber and logs. February 1915-July 1916 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: Lumber and logs. July 1916-May 1920 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: General expenses. October 1917-November 1919 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: Depreciation records. 1914-1915 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: General accounts receivable, balances. 1916 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: Cancelled voucher checks. 1918-1920 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Records: Report of the Coronado Railroad, Arizona Copper Company, Ltd. to the Corporation Commission of the State of Arizona for the year ending, June 30, 1913 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Items. 1889-1912 (Box 74)
    Includes:
    five letters (1889, 1894, 1912)
    mining telegraph message code (1908)
    work sheets for supplies including coke, coal, and fuel oil (1912)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Cost Statement. November 1914-December 1921 (Box 75, Folder 1-6)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Direct Mining Costs. December 1907-February 1922 (Box 76, Folder 1-6)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Air drill, machine and standard shifts. June 1912-July 1919 (Box 77, Folder 1-3)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Air charges. March 1914-December 1921 (Box 77, Folder 4-5)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Air drill expenses. July 1914-September 1920 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Air drill repair costs. October 1917-September 1919, December 1922 (Box 78, Folder 1-2)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Power statement. April 1914-September 1921 (Box 78, Folder 3-4)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Connections and development. September 1913-September 1916 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Electric haulage costs. October 1913-April 1921 (Box 78, Folder 6-7)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Footage costs. January 1917-December 1921 (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Footage reports. May 1913-February 1922 (Box 79, Folder 3-6)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Segregation of accounts. October 1914-December 1921 (Box 80, Folder 1-9)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Monthly abstracts of labor and materials. November 1909-September 1914 (Box 81, Folder 1-6)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Monthly abstracts of labor and materials. October 1914-September 1918 (Box 82, Folder 1-4)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Monthly abstracts of labor and materials. October 1918-December 1921 (Box 83, Folder 1-5)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Segregation of tonnages. October 1913-September 1915 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Monthly report. July 1913-December 1921 (Box 84, Folder 2-5)
  - Longfellow Mining Department: Production records. 1907-1919 (Box 84, Folder 6-9)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Air charges. December 1917-December 1921 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Air drill expenses. February 1917-September 1920 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Cost statements. January 1918-September 1920 (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Direct mining costs. January 1917-June 1922 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Electric haulage costs. March 1920-April 1921 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Power statements. January 1917-September 1921 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Segregation of accounts. February 1917-December 1921 (Box 86, Folder 1-3)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Monthly abstracts. May 1917-March 1921 (Box 86, Folder 4-6)
    Note: abstracts for 1911-1913 and April-October 1921 are combined with the Metcalf Monthly Abstracts. See box 88.
  - Coronado Mining Department: Footage costs. April 1917-December 1921 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Coronado Mining Department: Miscellaneous reports. (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Air charges and air drill expenses. December 1917-April 1919 and April 1917-September 1919 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Cost statements. November 1917-September 1919 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Direct mining costs. June 1917-April 1919 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Footage costs. May 1918-April 1919 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Segregation of accounts. June 1917-April 1921 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Standard air shifts and miscellaneous shift reports. December 1917-April 1919 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Metcalf Mining Department: Monthly abstracts. January 1911-December 1921 (Box 88, Folder 1-5)
  - Wage Account Check Register. November 1903-April 1904 (Volume 89)
  - Wage Account Check Register. April 1904-February 1905 (Volume 90)
  - Wage Account Check Register. February 1905-October 1905 (Volume 91)
  - Wage Account Check Register. October 1905-April 1906 (Volume 92)
  - Register of unclaimed wages. March 1915-September 1920 (Volume 93)
  - Mine location notes. 1885-1890 (Volume 94)
  - Contract mining journal. November 1903-February 1908 (Volume 95)
  - Cables received and dispatched. March 1907-August 1910 (Volume 96)
  - Scrap iron. February 1899-August 1914 (Volume 97)
  - Furnace report (smelter). January 1906-August 1914 (Volume 98)
  - Clifton Warehouse: Supply inventory. 1916-1918 (Box 99)
  - Financial Inventories. 1918-1921 (Volume 100)
- Series II: Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company Records, 1890-1919
  - Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company: Memo Cash Book. 1890-1895 (Volume 101)
  - Arizona and New Mexico Railway Company: Fuel oil records. 1916-1919 (Volume 102)
  - Railway Time Book. March -October 1900 (Volume 103)
  - Railway Time Book. February-October 1903 (Volume 104)
- Series III: Records of Injured Persons, 1912-1921
  - Compensation Payments to Injured Persons, no. 1-669. 1912-1914 (Box 105)
  - Compensation Payments to Injured Persons, no. 670-1499. 1914-1917 (Box 106)
  - Compensation Payments to Injured Persons, no. 1500-2000. 1917-1919 (Box 107)
  - Metcalf Hospital Record. 1916-1919 (Box 107)
  - Clifton Hospital Record. 1916-1921 (Box 108)
  - Hospital Accounts Receivable. 1916-1918 (Volume 109)
  - Mine Inspector: Report on Accidents. April 1913-September 1921 (Box 110, Folder 1-4)
  - Mining Department: Report of Personal Injury. 1919-1921 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Summary of Injuries to Persons. October 1912-September 1915 (Volume 111)
- Series IV: Production and Sales Records, 1893-1921
  - Ore, Coke and Copper Record. October 1893-December 1905 (Volume 112)
  - Ore, Coke and Copper Record. February 1906-September 1915 (Volume 113)
  - Copper Costs. October 1905-December 1909 (Volume 114)
  - Copper Sales and Proceeds. October 1913-October 1921 (Volume 115)
  - Copper Sales. May 1916-December 1917 (Volume 116)
  - Copper Record: Production and Shipment. January 1916-December 1921 (Volume 117)
- Series V: Miscellaneous Financial Records (Microfiche), 1909-1921
  - Cost Sheets. December 1909-September 1914 (Box 118)
  - Mining Cost Sheets (General Office). January 1917-March 1915 (Box 118)
  - Production Costs (Coronado). April 1905 (Box 118)
  - Abstract Journal. July 1911-January 1920 (Box 118)
  - Rent Records. 1912-1920 (Box 118)
  - Rent Records: Clifton. 1918-1920 (Box 118)
  - Rent Records: Longfellow. 1918-1920 (Box 118)
  - Rent Records: Metcalf/Coronado. 1912-1920 (Box 118)
  - Ground Rent: Metcalf/Coronado. 1912-1920 (Box 118)
  - Payroll Records: Longfellow. 1914-1921 (Box 118)
  - Payroll Records: Coronado. 1914-1921 (Box 118)
  - Payroll Records: Metcalf. 1914-1921 (Box 118)
  - Payroll Records: Clifton. 1914-1921 (Box 118)
  - Payroll Records: Smelter. 1914-1921 (Box 118)
  - Voucher Records. 1910-1920 (Box 118)
  - Light Ledgers for Longfellow, Metcalf and Coronado. 1916-1920 (Box 118)